DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宮飯》
On the third basement floor of the dungeon,
在迷宮的地下三層
through the underground graveyard and past the forest of the spire,
通過地下墓地，穿越尖塔之森
you reach the Golden Castle.
便會通到黃金城堡內部
The once splendid castle
曾經繁榮一時的城堡內
is now covered in mold and dust and is a shadow of what it used to be.
如今布滿黴菌與塵埃 昔日光景不復存在
The footsteps that come as if from nowhere,
不知從何處傳來的腳步聲
could they belong to an adventurer?
究竟屬於冒險者的？
Or could they belong to a former resident who has passed away
還是死後仍在徘徊流離的
but is still wandering around?
昔日居民的？
That's a Skeleton.
那是骷髏
And they're humans.
這是人類
That's a ghoul.
那是食屍鬼
How can you tell? You're creeping me out!
你怎麼知道啊？好嚇人！
The footsteps of a living creature, bones, and something rotten
生物、骨頭和腐爛物的腳步聲
are totally different.
截然不同啊
Let's go left.
往左邊走吧
The Golem is guarding the right passage.
右邊好像有巨魔像在戒備著
A Golem is a human-shaped magical creature made of mud, dirt, and stone.
巨魔像是以泥巴、土壤、石頭 組成的一種人形魔法生物
It is used as a puppet that faithfully follows
會遵從主人下達的命令
its master's commands.
被用來當作忠實的人偶
Stop.
等一下
For your information, Golems are 99% dirt!
話先說在前頭 巨魔像有99%都是土！
They aren't edible!
不能吃喔！
They are genuinely magical creatures!
那些傢伙是貨真價實的魔法生物！
I even know how to make them!
我連做法都知道！
-Teach me! -No!
-教我吧！ -不行！
What do you want to use them for after you learn how to make them?
你知道做法後要拿來幹嘛？
What I'm interested in is their bodies.
老夫是對巨魔像的身體感興趣
Follow me.
跟著老夫走吧
This is the campsite I usually use as my base.
這裡是老夫平時作為據點的營地
You live here?
你住在這裡？
I hardly sleep here.
很少會過夜
I usually hunt on the second or fourth floor,
基本上都是在第二層或第四層狩獵
and once a month, I shop for seasoning and other things I lack in town.
每個月到鎮上採購 調味料等缺少的物資
It was on my way back from a shopping trip that I met you folks.
當時與你們相遇 也是在老夫採購的回程上
There are only a few monsters you can eat on the third floor.
第三層能夠食用的魔物很少
They are mostly decayed or just bones.
大部分不是腐爛了，就是只剩骨頭
But…
不過呢…
Golems!
巨魔像！
Those wonderful creatures are different!
那美妙的生物不一樣！
Their bodies are high in nutrition
巨魔像的身體富含大量營養素
and always maintain the appropriate temperature and humidity.
總是保有適當的溫度與濕度
In other words,
所以換句話說
you are using Golems as a garden?
你把巨魔像當作田地啊？
The people in this castle will weep!
城堡裡的人聽到後會哭啦！
And so will the scholars of magic!
魔法研究者也會跟著哭！
Why?
為什麼？
I don't like magic, but those creatures deserve praise.
老夫雖然不喜歡魔法 但巨魔像值得讚賞
All gardens should be like that!
所有農田都應該像那樣！
After all, they're resistant to harmful insects.
畢竟巨魔像不容易長害蟲
And they drive away vegetable thieves.
還會驅趕偷菜賊
I don't think they're after the vegetables.
對方的目的不是要偷菜吧
What's more, they even control moisture levels.
而且還會控制濕度
If you plant seeds and seedlings in them,
只要播種或插苗
they'll take care of the rest of the cultivation.
之後巨魔像就會自行幫忙培育
That said, you still have to tend them carefully.
話是這麼說 但還是不能缺少細微的照顧
That's why I have my base here.
所以老夫才會在這裡設立據點
Here they come!
有好多隻都出現了！
What now?
你要怎麼做？
-Need our help? -No need!
-需要幫忙嗎？ -不用！
Wow.
好強啊
He's used to this.
他很熟練呢
How does he know where the Golem's core is located?
他怎麼會知道巨魔像的核心在哪？
Don't tell me…
該不會…
It's done.
結束囉
Harvest the vegetables from the Golems.
幫忙從巨魔像身上採收蔬菜吧
I thought they were covered in green, but are these all vegetables?
從剛才就覺得好像很茂密 這些全部都是蔬菜？
From a Golem's perspective, aren't they like parasites?
從巨魔像的角度來看 不就像是被寄生嗎？
On the contrary, the plants' roots make the soil firmer,
植物扎根反而會讓土壤變穩固
so you could say they're in a symbiotic relationship.
所以可以說是共生關係
Are you sure?
真的假的？
But please remove the weeds.
不過雜草記得要拔掉喔
What a rich harvest!
大豐收…
Looks like we can finally enjoy some normal vegetables!
看來終於可以久違 吃到普通的蔬菜了！
Bring the weeds over here.
雜草拿到這裡來
Stack them up in this spot and they will wither.
堆放在這附近就會乾枯
Once they're withered,
枯萎之後
I'll return them to the Golems' bodies, and they'll naturally decompose.
埋回巨魔像的身體裡就會自然分解
And this is fertilizer I made elsewhere.
然後這些是在別處製作的肥料
I mix this into the Golems!
再將其混進巨魔像裡！
I knew it!
果然沒錯！
You knew what?
果然沒錯？
You knew where the Golems' cores were because you're the one who planted them!
你會知道巨魔像核心的位置 是因為那是你埋進去的吧！
Unbelievable.
太令我無語了
It's illegal to activate a magical creature without permission!
激活未經許可的魔法生物 是犯罪行為耶！
All I'm doing is digging up dirt and putting it back.
老夫只是翻動土壤 將其恢復原狀而已
So, you're bypassing the law!
所以是規避法律的魔法生物？
Stir the soil well and make raised rows.
仔細混合土壤，堆成田畦
Planting the same crop repeatedly leads to monocropping issues,
種植相同植物會引發連作障礙
so sow the seeds in a different Golem.
所以播種的巨魔像要錯開
I'm exhausted.
好累啊
I feel like I used more stamina than when fighting monsters.
感覺比和魔物戰鬥消耗更多體力
Thanks to your help, it got done much quicker.
多虧有你們幫忙，速度快多了
Drinking water made me want to use the bathroom.
喝水之後好想上廁所
Well then, while that elven girl is gone,
現在趁那位精靈女孩不在的期間
I'll gather up the scattered soil as much as I can.
把鬆散的土壤盡量集中起來
Taro, Jiro, Saburo.
太郎、次郎、三郎
Will burying those make them revive quickly?
把那些埋進去就會馬上復活嗎？
No, it takes some time.
不，需要一些時間
They'll revive just when the seeds begin to take root,
正好會在種子扎好根
and the soil stays in place even when they move around.
土壤移動也不會散落的時候
He treats the Golems with so much care.
他對待巨魔像的方式充滿了愛呢
I'm impressed.
真了不起
So this is how you were living.
原來這就是你的生活方式啊
Wasn't it tough?
你不覺得辛苦嗎？
I do it because I like it.
老夫是因為喜歡才做的
It's not tough at all.
一點也不覺得辛苦
That's about it.
大概就這樣吧
Now, let's enjoy the fruits of our labor!
現在來享受勞動的成果吧！
What a beautiful color.
顏色好漂亮
I've sure gotten better at peeling.
我的削皮技術也進步了
Is this size really okay?
切這麼大塊真的可以嗎？
It's perfect.
可以
Are you making a fire? I can do it for you.
要點火嗎？我來吧
I'll strike a flint, so it's fine.
不需要，用打火石點就好
You always make a fire like that, but using magic is faster.
你總是那樣點火，用魔法明明比較快
You were just singing the praises of how convenient Golems are.
你不久前不是才開心地稱讚 巨魔像很方便嗎？
When you make something easier, you may lose your edge in a skill.
選擇用輕鬆的方式解決 就會導致某項技能退步
Convenience and ease aren't the same thing.
方便和安逸是不同的
Your method is no different from buying vegetables from the store.
你的做法和去商店直接買菜沒有不同
This is the last of the Basilisk bacon.
巴西利斯克培根剩最後一塊了
It's done.
完成了
FRESH VEGETABLE LUNCH FROM THE GOLEM GARDEN
（巨魔像田園鮮蔬午餐）
-Let's dig in!
-開動了！
It's so good!
超級好吃！
It's odd to think such tasty vegetables can grow underground!
竟然能在這樣的地底下 種出如此美味的菜，真不可思議！
I wonder if something inside the Golems is affecting the flavor.
或許是巨魔像身上的 某種成分影響了味道呢
Stop it!
別那樣說！
I don't care if they walk or yell. They're gardens!
就算會走路還是會叫喊，那都是田！
Speaking of which, Golems are 99% soil, right?
話說回來，巨魔像有99%是土對吧？
What's the last 1%?
那剩下的1%是什麼？
It's a secret.
祕密
Phew, that was delicious.
天啊，太好吃了
I'm so full.
吃得好飽
I'm feeling sleepy after eating so much.
飽餐一頓之後就想睡覺了
You can rest.
你們可以休息沒關係
There's a little something I want to take care of.
老夫還有一點事要處理
Clean up!
要自己收拾！
I'm going to the toilet.
老夫去一下廁所
The toilets around here are so proper.
這附近的廁所規劃得很好呢
They aren't some random holes dug in the ground.
不是隨便挖個洞而已
In busy areas of the dungeon,
迷宮裡行人較多的地方
there are designated spots for people to relieve themselves.
設有可以解決內急的廁所
They're always kept clean,
環境總是很乾淨
and sometimes they're even decorated with flowers.
偶爾還會裝飾花朵之類的
There must be some diligent people here.
看來有勤奮的人在呢
Hm?
嗯？
Senshi!
先西！
What is it?
怎麼了？
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛？
I'm collecting the feces and urine and carrying them to the chamber pots.
老夫在收集廁所的糞尿，運去肥料缸
I'm impressed you can do that right after a meal.
真佩服你能在吃飽後做這件事
They serve as crucial fertilizers down here.
這些是此地重要的肥料之一
You mean they were also used for the vegetables…
那麼剛才的蔬菜也…
Marcille, they do the same thing on the surface, too.
瑪露希爾，那點和地面上是一樣的吧
I know that, but it's still gross.
是沒錯啦，但總覺得很反感
Why are you so determined to stick to your life in the dungeon?
先西為什麼如此 執著於迷宮裡的生活呢？
If you want a self-sufficient life, you could have it above ground as well.
要自給自足的話在地面上也做得到啊
Don't you think it'd be easier to cultivate a garden outside and hunt?
你不會覺得在外面 耕田和狩獵比較輕鬆嗎？
Then who else will maintain the toilets in the dungeon?
那樣的話，誰要來維護迷宮的廁所？
Who will remove the zombies that fall inside the toilets?
誰要來除掉摔進廁所裡的殭屍？
Who will help up the fallen Golems?
誰能來扶起倒下的巨魔像？
There used to be over ten Golems, but now there are only three.
以前巨魔像的數量超過十隻 如今只剩三隻
Without Golems,
要是巨魔像消失
monsters from the lower levels will climb up here.
較低等的魔物就會跑上來
And the monsters driven out by those monsters will enter other places.
被那些傢伙趕跑的其他魔物 又會闖入其他地方
And they will drive out other monsters.
然後換那批魔物再驅趕別的同族
If that happens, this dungeon will be a different place.
若發生那種事，這裡就會完全變了樣
You wouldn't be able to stroll or hunt in here.
不管是行走或狩獵 都無法隨心所欲地進行
The dungeon is just like a garden.
迷宮和農田都一樣
You can't abandon them and expect to reap their rewards.
不能棄之不顧又想享受好處
More than anything,
更重要的是
eating the things that grow here and giving back to the dungeon…
食用這裡栽種的農作物並回饋給迷宮
Living like this, I finally feel like I've truly entered this dungeon.
持續那樣的生活後 才終於覺得自己真正融入了這座迷宮
And that makes me happy.
那讓老夫十分開心
But if that's the case,
但那樣的話
is it okay for you to leave this place on our behalf?
你為了我們離開這裡沒問題嗎？
If this place falls into chaos…
這一帶要是荒廢…
Don't worry about it.
不用擔心
Even if I'm away for a month or two, the Golems will take care of things.
只是離開一到兩個月的話 巨魔像會幫忙打理的
Besides, I wouldn't rest easy at night if you all died from malnutrition.
而且你們若因為營養不良而死掉 老夫也會良心不安
Give me a minute.
在這等一下
I'll get ready in a hurry.
老夫會盡快做好準備
Senshi is so amazing.
先西真是了不起
What are you going to do with these vegetables?
這些蔬菜要怎麼辦？
I usually use them for bartering.
平時老夫會用來以物易物
Sometimes I set up an unmanned booth and sell them.
或設立無人商店販賣
An unmanned booth?
無人商店？
I used to collect the money in a treasure box,
之前採用讓買家自己 放錢到寶箱的方式
but I stopped because they kept getting stolen.
但錢總是被偷走，所以就沒再那樣做
So that's why that treasure box…
所以那個寶箱…
…Always had money in it.
才會總是裝著錢
So, do you do your bartering around here?
以物易物是在這附近進行嗎？
I have customers on a lower floor,
再下去幾層有老主顧
but even if we go now, they probably won't have time for us.
但現在過去對方應該不會接受交易吧
I didn't want to leave the garden lying idle,
老夫不想閒置田地
so I harvested the crops.
所以就把作物採收了
But you can throw them away if you don't need them.
但用不到的話丟掉也罷
You can't do that! You shouldn't waste food!
千萬不行！要珍惜食物！
You worked so hard to cultivate them, and they're so glossy and delicious!
你辛辛苦苦把蔬菜 栽種得這麼有光澤又美味！
You're growing attached to them.
已經產生感情了呢
Well, in that case, we really should trade them around here.
那我們果然得在這附近找人交易
-Around here, huh?
-這附近啊？
There are merchants even inside the dungeon.
迷宮裡也有商人
Enter.
進來吧
Many of their customers are adventurers
大多數的客人都是冒險者
or people who, for reasons, can't go back above ground.
或因故無法返回地面的人
Welcome, my dear guests.
歡迎光臨，客人
Are you looking for a place to stay or something to eat?
今天要住宿還是用餐？
We want to trade.
我們要交易
Well, well.
這樣啊…
So, what do you have?
那各位要拿什麼做交易呢？
Vegetables.
蔬菜
Go away, go away!
給我滾回去！
Wait, at least listen to…
等等，至少聽我們說…
If you want to trade, bring coins!
要交易就拿錢過來！
Do you understand? Coins!
懂嗎？我說的是錢！
The round, shiny, and glittery things!
又圓又亮的那個金色物體！
It's not like we want to trade them for gems.
我們沒有要交換寶石
You have a kitchen here, don't you?
這裡不是有廚房嗎？
You need ingredients…
你會用到食材…
These are round and shiny, too.
這作物也是又圓又亮呀
Show this carrot to your cook.
把這紅蘿蔔拿給廚師看吧
I'm sure they'll want to use it.
他們一定會想拿去煮的
Who would eat something so disgusting?!
誰要吃那種噁心的東西啦！
How awful!
太過分了！
You'll incur divine punishment if you waste food!
你這樣糟蹋食物會遭天譴的！
Throw them out now!
快把這些傢伙攆出去！
-Quickly now! -Listen to--
-快點！ -聽我們說…
Huh?
怎麼了？
Orcs!
是半獸人！
Kill the ones with weapons first!
先從有武器的人開始殺！
Don't leave even one alive!
一個活口都不留！
Why are orcs here?
為何會出現半獸人？
I thought they were on much lower floors.
這些傢伙不是應該 在更深層的地方嗎？
Anyway, we have to run…
別說了，總之我們快逃…
-Marcille! -Wait.
-瑪露希爾！ -等一下
What are you doing here, Senshi?
你怎麼會在這種地方？先西
That's what I want to ask as well.
老夫也想問你這個問題
Are these folks your acquaintances?
他們是你認識的人嗎？
That's right.
沒錯
To think you would associate with humans and an elf.
沒想到你會跟人類和精靈結伴
By customers, did you mean…
你說的老主顧該不會…
I meant them.
就是他們
I figured he meant folks like them, but orcs, huh?
雖然早就預想到會是這種情況 不過原來是半獸人啊？
I thought they'd be goblins at least.
我以為頂多就是哥布林
I assumed he meant Kobolds.
我還以為是狗頭人
The Red Dragon showed up.
炎龍出現了
The Red Dragon that rarely appeared in the past.
以往極少現身的炎龍
But lately, it's been showing up near our settlement.
最近開始在我們村落附近出沒
There are some who can't fight in our settlement.
我們的聚落裡有些人不能戰鬥
We came to this floor for temporary refuge.
為了暫時避難才會來到這一層
The Red Dragon, could it be?
他說的炎龍該不會就是那隻吧？
The Dragon, where did you see it?
你是在哪裡看到那隻龍的？
Are you asking me to tell you where our settlement is?
要我向你們說出村落的位置？
I refuse.
我拒絕
Boss, we dealt with everyone inside.
老大，裡面搞定了
Good.
很好
Carry out everything that might be useful.
把看起來能用的東西全部搬出來
What on earth?
這是什麼東西？
Rotten milk?
壞掉的牛奶嗎？
Throw it away.
丟掉吧
Those are crops you cultivated, right?
那些是你種的農作物吧？
As you can see, we're in need right now.
如你所見，我們現在開支很大
I'd like you to share that with me.
可以的話希望你可以分給我們
For barter?
以物易物嗎？
In that case, these are…
是那樣的話，這些…
No.
不
As I said,
我說過了吧？
we can't afford that right now.
我們現在手頭很緊
It pains me to ask this of a friend,
拜託朋友這種事實在讓我心痛
but I want you to give us all the stuff you have there.
但可以把身上的東西全部交出來嗎？
S-Senshi.
先西
Very well.
好吧
Good.
太好了
But in exchange, I have a favor to ask you.
不過條件是你要答應老夫一個請求
Tonight, let us stay at your place.
今晚讓我們借住在你們的營地吧
-Huh?
-什麼？
If you will grant us that,
只要你同意
we will gladly offer our lives or our vegetables.
不管是生命或蔬菜我們都會乖乖奉上
Huh?
什麼？
And you there!
還有那邊的你！
That isn't rotten, it's fermented!
那食品不是壞掉，是發酵了！
Be sure to take it with you!
一定要帶回去！
Why did you say that?
你為何要那樣說啊？
They took our weapons.
他們連我們的武器都沒收了
If we learn the location of their campsite,
一旦知道他們營地的地點
we'll never see the light of day again.
我們就無法再回到地表了
You do have a plan, right?
你是有什麼考量吧？
The jar I told an orc to take earlier
剛才老夫交代半獸人要帶回去的瓶子
is leaven made of yeast.
那是酵母製成的麵種
And the orcs have the flour that was in the kitchen.
而且半獸人也帶走了 剛才那間廚房的麵粉
In other words…
也就是說…
In other words?
也就是說？
I can make bread!
可以做麵包！
-Moron! -So you don't have a plan!
-笨蛋！ -原來不是有什麼計劃嗎？
-You just wanted to make bread!
-你竟然只是想做麵包！
Moron!
笨蛋！
Hey, there! Be quiet!
喂，你們幾個！給我安靜點！
It's an elf!
是精靈！
What a barbaric face.
多麼野蠻的長相啊
Stay inside this cage.
進去這個圍欄裡
Dad came back!
爸爸回來了！
We better not end up becoming their meal for today.
我們最終不會成為 他們今天的食材吧？
Where did you put the leaven?!
把那罐麵種拿去哪了？
If you don't know how to use it, you're sitting on a gold mine!
你不知道要怎麼用 那根本是白白浪費好東西！
Give it to me! I'll make you bread!
拿過來，老夫幫你們做麵包！
Bread!
麵包…
Mix together strong wheat flour, salt, sugar, leaven, and water.
將高筋麵粉、鹽巴、砂糖 麵種與水混合
And knead it until it comes together.
揉捏再攪拌到成團為止
Are you playing with mud?
你們在玩泥巴嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
How about a history lesson?
來學習歷史吧
This is a story about a time when we were still living above ground
以前我們沒住在地底下
instead of under the ground.
而是生活在地面上
People like that elf and humans there
那裡的精靈和人類們
killed many of our people and took our lands.
殺害了我們的許多夥伴並搶走了領土
Orcs killed a lot of other races, too.
半獸人不是也殺了 很多其他種族的生物嗎？
What?
你說什麼？
Now, you add olive oil.
這時加入橄欖油
We were forced to leave the surface and after wandering for a while,
被趕離地面的我們到處流浪
we found our place underground, and we had peace for a while.
最後在地底下找到棲身之地 暫時過上一段平穩的日子
Until they found us again.
直到再度被他們找到為止
Hold the edge of the dough and knead it by punching it down.
抓起麵團的邊緣，用摔打的方式揉捏
They poured oil into the underground and set fire to it.
那群傢伙在地底下倒油放火
That's because you orcs kept raiding the villages of other races over and over!
還不都是因為你們 不斷掠奪其他種族村落的東西！
It was the only way for us to survive.
我們不那麼做就活不下去
That was your way of life even before you moved underground.
你們還沒搬到地底生活前 就是那種行事作風啊
That's why you were driven out!
所以才會被趕走！
Stop it, Marcille. That's enough--
別說了，瑪露希爾，別太過分…
Shut up, half-foot!
給我閉嘴，半身人！
Knead it with more strength, will you?!
揉捏時再出點力行不行啊？
Sorry.
抱歉
Give it to me! I'll do it!
拿來！我來揉！
We were driven from the surface and fled underground.
我們被趕離地面，逃到地底
And when we finally arrived at the dungeon,
就連好不容易找到的迷宮
you folks tried to take it from us!
你們也想奪走！
It was the villagers above ground who found it first!
最先發現迷宮的是地表上方的村民！
But we went into the depths first!
但最早潛入深處的是我們！
Then the zombies roaming around were there before anyone else!
如果照你的邏輯 在附近遊蕩的殭屍比你們更早啦！
Once the dough stretches smoothly, it's time for the first fermentation.
揉到麵團能順利拉長後 進行第一次發酵
When the dough doubles in size, divide it evenly and shape it neatly.
等它膨脹到約兩倍大 再平均分割並整圓
You've been silent this whole time, tall-man.
你一直都保持沉默呢，高個子
But what are you thinking?
你又是怎麼想的？
They say anyone who defeats the lunatic magician who built this place
據世人所說，打倒創建 這座迷宮的瘋狂魔法師
will gain this whole castle.
就能獲得整座城堡
Why are you trying to go to the depths of the dungeon?
你前往迷宮深處是為了什麼？
When you gain the kingdom, what will you do?
當你獲得王國，你會怎麼做？
I've heard of that story, but I've never thought of that.
我聽過那個傳聞 但從來沒有想過這問題
What a joke.
真是讓我無言以對
All adventurers are like you.
所謂的冒險者盡是像你的一幫人
You make your daily wage and you test your skills.
一心想著要賺日薪或試身手
You're all just greedy fools.
你們都是自私自利的蠢貨
I shudder to think what might happen if someone like you
想到這座城堡要是落入你這種人手中
ends up getting this castle.
就令我不寒而慄
That's why we kill anyone from the surface we can find.
這就是我們看到地表上的人 就一律殺害的原因
What a poor excuse!
那只是歪理吧！
Then you should compete for the throne as well.
既然如此，你們也去爭取坐上王座啊
Or is plundering the only thing orcs can do?
還是說半獸人會做的事就只有掠奪？
At least you have spunk.
你只有氣勢倒是不錯嘛
I like that.
我喜歡
I'll throw you into the fire alive!
我要把你活生生地扔進火堆裡！
See? You turn to violence so quickly!
看吧，你就是愛動不動就訴諸暴力！
Second fermentation.
第二次發酵
Once it has expanded enough,
在麵團膨脹到一定的程度之後
cook it on low heat one side at a time.
用小火一面一面烤
Let it steam a little,
稍微蒸一下
and open the lid.
接著打開鍋蓋
And the bread is done!
麵包就完成了！
It smells so good!
好香喔！
Let's have a taste.
來試吃吧
Stop! That bread is ours.
等一下！那些麵包是我們的東西
We won't give it to you.
不是給你們吃的
What?
什麼？
I let you make bread because you wanted to,
你說想做麵包，所以我答應了
but what we do with it is up to us.
不過要怎麼處理麵包是我們的自由
Dad.
爸爸
These people made it together, but they don't get to eat it?
明明是大家一起做的 他們卻不能吃麵包嗎？
That's because bread alone won't make a meal.
因為只吃麵包不能算是一餐呀
You need a staple food, meat, and vegetables for a well-balanced meal.
要有主食、主菜、配菜 吃得均衡才是好的一餐
Your father just wanted us to wait until the other dishes were ready.
你爸爸是要我們等到其他料理也煮好
Hey! What are you saying?!
喂，你在那邊胡說什麼？
Exactly. He promised to provide lodging for a night
沒錯，他答應要招待我們留宿一晚
in exchange for our vegetables.
以換取我們的蔬菜
And your father is someone who can't break promises.
你父親可是不會食言的男人
Hey! Make them some random food!
喂！給他們隨便煮點東西！
FRESHLY PICKED STEWED CABBAGE
（剛搶來的高麗菜燉肉）
Here! It's ready!
來！煮好了！
-Eat! -Okay.
-吃吧！ -好
Thank you.
我開動了
I-It's good!
好好吃喔！
So spicy!
超辣的！
It's spicy and delicious!
又辣又美味！
It's made with the same ingredients as Senshi's stewed cabbage,
使用的食材 明明和先西的燉高麗菜一樣
but it's a completely different dish.
卻化為截然不同的料理呢
I said plundering was the only thing you could do,
我剛才說半獸人只會掠奪
but orcs can be pretty decent, too.
但你們其實滿有一套的嘛
Shut up.
少囉嗦
Um…
那個…
You asked me why I was trying to reach the depths of the dungeon.
關於我前往迷宮深處的原因
You see, my sister was eaten by the Red Dragon.
那是因為我妹妹被炎龍吃了
That's why I'm going after the Dragon.
所以我正在追那隻龍
If you will tell us where it is, we'll defeat the Red Dragon.
只要你肯說出地點 我們就會打倒炎龍
We won't involve your settlement at all.
絕對不會干涉你們的村落
I promise.
我向你保證
Hey, bring me a map.
喂，把地圖拿來
Got it.
好的
It's two floors under this one.
要從這裡往下兩層
Last time I saw it, it was around the west residential area.
我們最後一次見到牠 是在西邊居住區附近
Thank you.
謝謝你
From now on, I'll think about the possibility
從現在起我在探索的同時
of gaining this dungeon as I explore it.
會好好思考獲得這座迷宮後要怎麼做
It's tough to imagine a guy who gets captured by an orc
我很難想像被半獸人抓走
and bakes bread will become a king.
還做麵包的傢伙會成為國王
But good luck.
不過你好好加油吧
It tastes really good.
好好吃喔
You know, that cabbage was grown on the back of a Golem.
我跟你說喔，那些高麗菜 是從巨魔像的背上長出來的
Even though people have varying views, they all experience hunger.
即使想法有所差異 會感到飢餓這點大家都是相同的
It may only be dungeon food, but it's still dungeon food.
儘管只是迷宮飯，但也不容小覷
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：沈庭葦